ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Grabelski, Jeffrey, Collection of Training Materials /4354/005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Jeffrey Grabelski Collection of Training Materials
1980- 2006
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Grabelski, Jeffrey
New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (NYSSILR)
New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Metropolitan District Office
/4354/005
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Instructional and educational works, records (documents).
This collection consists of training materials and pamphlets for and about the building trades. They were collected by Cornell faculty member Jeffrey Grabelski.
10608075
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, February 04, 2019
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Jeffrey Grabelsky is the Associate Director of The Worker Institute at Cornell. He develops and delivers education and training programs and provides research and technical assistance in all aspects of union affairs. He began his career in the labor movement working and organizing in the steel industry in 1973, has been a member of the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) for thirty years, and is the former national organizing director of the Building and Construction Trades Department (AFL-CIO).
After September 11, 2001, Professor Grabelsky represented the Building and Construction Trades Council of Greater New York on the World Trade Center Emergency Project Labor-Management Partnership.
Professor Grabelsky is currently co-coordinating the Construction Career Opportunities Project, a joint initiative involving Cornell University, the Partnership for Working Families, and the Building and Construction Trades Department. He is also representing the Building and Construction Trades Department on the Emerald Cities Initiative as a Special Assistant to President Mark Ayers.
Professor Grabelsky also co-authored the trainer's manuals for the UBCJA and IBEW national steward training programs, COMET (Construction Organizing Membership Education Training), COMET II (Worksite Organizing with COMET Activists), MEMO (Membership Education and Mobilization for Organizing), and the AFL-CIO Voice at Work Membership Mobilization Programs.
Professor Grabelsky received his B.A. in Political Science from the University of Michigan, his M.A. in U.S. Labor History from Syracuse University, his M.S. in Industrial and Labor Relations from Cornell University, and his Journeyman Electrician Classification from the IBEW.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4352: Lois Gray Collection of Training Materials /4068: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office, Anne Nelson Papers /4026: ILR School Metropolitan Office Extension Division Completed Questionnaires on Union Activity /4296: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.) Training Manuals /4296 AV: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.) Training Audio-Visual Materials /4321 AV: ILR School Smithers Institute Audio-Visual Materials /4354/005 MB: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Jeffrey Grabelski Memorabilia
Building trades > Employees > Labor unions; Construction workers > Labor unions; Hazardous substances > New York (State) > Safety measures.; Industrial sites > New York (State) > Safety measures.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Metropolitan District Office
10608075
- Trainers Manual: Foundation for the future - Comprehensive Construction Steward System (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Trainers Manual: Foundation for the future - Comprehensive Construction Steward System (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Governing Board of Presidents (September 19,1997) Pittsburgh, PA (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Building Trades Organizing Project
- Governing Board of Presidents (January 1999) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- COMET Evaluation: A Report on the Impact and Value of Multi-trade COMET I and COMET II Train-their-Trainer Courses, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Joint Labor-Management Health and Safety Committee at the World Trade Center Emergency Project, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Building and Construction Trades Council of Greater New York; Building Trades Employers' Association
- George Strauss, "Unions in the Building Trades: A case study" (Box 1, Folder 7)
- New York State AFL-CIO Strategic Review and Evaluation Project (April 21, 2006) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- How Contractors Can Improve Jobsite Productivity and Profits by Peter A. Cockshaw (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Craft Training in Open Shop Construction - The business roundtable (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CICE The Next Five Years and Beyond (May 1988) - The Business Roundtable (Box 1, Folder 11)
- More Construction for Money (The Business RoundTable) - January 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Measuring Productivity in Construction (The Business Roundtable) - September 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Construction Labor Motivation (The Business Roundtable) -August 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Improving Construction Safety Performance (The Business Roundtable) - January 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- First and Second Level Supervisory Training (The Business Roundtable) - May 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Management Education and Academic Relations (The Business Roundtable) - June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Modern Management Systems (The Business Roundtable) - November 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Contractual Arrangements (The Business Roundtable) -October 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Integrating Construction Resources and Technology into Engineering (The Business Roundtable) - August, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Technological Progress in the Construction Industry (The Business Roundtable) -July 1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Construction Technology Needs and Priorities (The Business Roundtable) - August 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Exclusive Jurisdiction in Construction (The Business Roundtable) -July 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Contractor Supervision in Unionized Construction (The Business Roundtable) - February 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Constraints Imposed by Collective Bargaining Agreements (The Business Roundtable) - September 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Local Labor Practices (The Business Roundtable) - Abril 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Absenteeism and Turnover (The Business Roundtable) -June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- The Impact of Local Union Politics (The Business Roundtable) -June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Subjourneymen in Union Construction (The Business Roundtable) - February 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Government Limitations on Training Innovations (The Business Roundtable) -March 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Construction Training Through Vocational Education (The Business Roundtable) -August 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Training Problems in Open Shop Construction (The Business Roundtable) -September 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Labor Supply Information (The Business Roundtable) -Abril 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Administration and Enforcement of Building Codes and Regulations (The Business Roundtable) - October 1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- The Roundtable Report - Schedule Overtime Effect on Construction Projects- November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Hazard Communication in Construction (folder 1 of 2), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Hazard Communication in Construction (folder 2 of 2), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Trainers Manual for the Comprehensive Construction Steward System (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Voice @ Work Freedom to Choose a Union (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Voice @ Work Freedom to Choose a Union (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 40)
- 2ND Edition Comet Trainer's Manual (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 41)
- 2ND Edition Comet Trainer's Manual (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 42)